

ABM MEHEDI HASAN MARKETING & ADMIN OPERATIONS

- R13/H31, Merul Badda, Dhaka 1212.
- 01865515986
- mehedi1923@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/mehedihasan1923/

PROFESSIONAL GOAL

To work with an organization where I can apply my knowledge and technical expertise through hard work, creativity and team play to carry out each task with a view to achieving the best possible results and enhancing my professional skills.

SPECIFIC QUALITIES

Computer Literacy

- System Software (Windows)
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Programs.
- Skillful in Power Point and Excel.
- Skill in Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator
- Good command over web browsing, E- mailing & any data collection
- Good command over Writing Bengali.

Soft Skills

- Competent enough to lead a team or work as a team member.
- Competent in problem solving and analytical tasks.
- Confident, positive, innovative, self-driven & goal oriented.
- Good in presentation, communication & interpersonal skills.
- Open minded in adapting new and challenging situations.
- · Fast learner and passionate for Innovation.
- · Able to meet targets and deadlines ontime.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

- Organisation Name- Agro Machinery Industry Limited.
- Location-Middle Badda, Dhaka.
- Time Period- Continuing
- Position Manager, Operations & Marketing.
- Organisation Name- FedEx Express.
- · Location-Banani. Dhaka.
- Time Period- 2010-2018
- Position Senior Executive, Marketing.
- Organisation Name- Warid Telecom (Pvt) Limited.
- Location-Gulshan-1. Dhaka.
- Time Period- 2008 -2010
- · Position Sales Officer.

Liaising with company stakeholders, planning events, managing admirative, sales support, social media activities; generate and apply with marketing tools. Gained expertise in publication marketing, Sales support, advertising, communications and admirative task. Looking to utilize my existing skill set to increase any company profitability.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

MBA (Masters of Business Administration)

- Major in Marketing.
- Passing Year 2006
- Southeast University, Dhaka
- CGPA 3.34 Out Of 4.00

B.Com (Bachelor of Commerce)

- Passing Year 1999
- National University.
- · Second Class.

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

- Rangpur Govt. College.
- Passing Year 1996
- Science Group
- · Second Division.

Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

- Thakurgaon Govt. Boys High School.
- Passing Year 1994
- Science Group
- First Division

Leadership Skills.

- Administrative/marketing responsibilities.
- Communications
- · Positive Thinking.
- · Flexibility.
- Execution & Monitoring.
- · Problem Solving.
- Positive Feedback.
- Integrity.
- · Building Relationship.
- · Communicating with management.

Languages Proficirency.

- · Bangla (Mother Tongue)
- · English Listening, Speaking & Writing.
- Hindi

Hobbies & Interests.



Writing



Designing



Tours & Travels



Playing Cricket



Listing Music

ADMINISTRATIVE DUTIES

- Ensure compliance of all administrative policies.
- Organize schedule meetings on time & take accurate minutes of meetings.
- · Generate and submit regularly scheduled reports to respective authority.
- Maintain supplies inventory by checking stock; placing and expediting orders for supplies; verifying receipt of supplies.
- Handle sensitive information in a confidential manner.
- Provide polite and professional communication
- · Implement clerical duties and administrative processes.
- Facilitate administrative, necessary functions and rovide support to team for smooth operations.
- · Responsible for overall company's administrative activities.
- · Training and developing capability.
- · Keeping close liaison with Bank, legal, and other all related department.
- Supervise / look after welfare and all kinds of administrative issues.
- Assist directly to Managing Director to maintain of all kinds of legal (YOY) company documents.
- Writing up purchase order, requisitions, contracts for the internal and external vendors, suppliers. Liaise with international suppliers and clients.

MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS DUTIES

- Overseeing branding, advertising, and promotional campaigns.
- Execution of all kind of ATL, BTL communications. .
- Create and excute email Marketing and keeping database.
- Overseeing, executions all kinds of Events, Fairs and campaigns.
- Coordinate with marketing and sales team on various campaigns, exhibitions, road show, Branch opening, Vehicle Branding etc Work closely with teams for develop media plans.
- Make design of all marketing collateral including promotional items, Flyers, sales folder, brochures and Letter head Pad, Envelope etc.
- Coordinated with sales teams to execute various campaigns both Govt & Non Govt Fairs and Exhibitions with the company's brand, images and Values.
- Promoting our brand at trade shows and major industry-related events.
- Preparing Govt/Non Govt Tenders of Agriculture extension programs following tender assessment rules.
- Time to time field Visit to improving/close the deal with Sales team as well as their Branding support needs.
- Keep updating YOUTUBE Channels, FB and Website editing.
- Execution of Events and worked closely with advertising agency and vendors.
- Ensuring making Daily, Weekly & Fortnightly panel advertising materials.
- † Drafted engaging, accurate and effective press releases.
- Managing the marketing department's staff.
- Works directy with senior management of the organization to develop marketing programs.
- Performs miscellaneous job-related duties as assigned.

REFERENCES

1. Md. Monirul Islam.

DGM- Production RFL Plastic Itd.

Mobile: +880 1841375378

2. Md. Asadur Rahman

Assistant Manager Direct Sales Mahindra & Mahidra Kurigram & Rangpur

Cell: 01844-471890

Email:asadur.rahman@rangsgroup.com

SOCIAL WORKS

- Up to the Mark experienced of organize, Planning, and Implementation of arrange FedEx cup and American Cup Golf tournaments with the Corporate Brand visibility of FedEx International Brand Guidelines at renowned Golf Gardens of the country executed Golf Tournament 2010-2017 (7 Years).
- Organized, executed with the team to Participate in Various JOB fair, Exhibitions, Events at Radisson Blue Hotel, Dhaka (2014 & 2016) With the Brand visibility of FedEx Express.
- ☑ Organized Field Demonstration programs and Farmers Training sessions/workshop to develop the administrative and product demonstration projects following Brand Guidelines of Agro Machinery Industry (AMI) Limited directly with the Farmers level to introduce modern farming machineries.
- Attending with the Teams in Field Examinations (Tests) following instructions of Bangladesh Agriculture Dept of Farm Mechanizations Projects in Dist/Upazila levels.

PARTICIPATIONS IN CSR ACTIVITIES

Worked closely as a supplier with Humanity First (an international charitable trust established to promote and safeguard the preservation of human life and dignity) Bangladesh Team.

PERSONAL INFORMATIONS.

Father's name: Md. Abdur Rashid
Mother's name: Mrs. Rezuana Akter
Date of Birth: 1st December 1978

• Permanent Address: 43/1, Rangpur Sadr, Rangpur 5400

Nationality: Bangladeshi

Religion: IslamCivil Status: Married.Blood Group: 0 +ve

National ID: 5550002066

• Generation: 1 (one)

• Height: 5 ft 8 Inch (approx.)

Sex : Male.

DECLARATION

I hereby certify the above information is truthfully accurate to the best of my knowledge and belief.

SIGNATURE: